这是斯普特尼克1号的声音，它是苏联在1957年发射的人类第一颗卫星
This is the sound of Sputnik, the very first artificial satellite, launched by the Soviet Union in 1957.
在2018年，太空叉将马一龙的特斯拉跑车射进了绕日轨道
In 2018, SpaceX launched Elon Musk’s Tesla Roadster into an orbit around the sun.
斯普特尼克1号在发射后几个月就落回地球
Sputnik fell back down to earth just a few months after it’s launch,
而马一龙的特斯拉现在也变成了不受控制的太空垃圾
and Elon’s Tesla is now just an uncontrollable piece of space debris.
天行者卢克：这坨垃圾
LUKE SKYWALKER: What a piece of junk
人类现在仍保持通信的卫星约有1700颗，它们都在环绕地球或者更远
There are around 1,700 operational satellites currently orbiting earth and beyond that we still communicate with.
但我们是如何和太空的物体通信的？
But how exactly do we communicate with objects in space?
本期视频我们将了解与太空中物体通信的不同方法
In this video, we’re going to look at the different ways that we communicate with objects,
物体囊括了从近地轨道的卫星到太阳系边缘的深空探测器
all the way from low Earth orbiting satellites to deep space probes at the edge of our solar system.
我们还将了解通信使用的设备
We’re also going to talk about the equipment that’s used
以及这些设备是怎样不断升级
and how the capability of that equipment has to grow,
以应付我们从太阳系获取到的不断增加的数据量
in order to deal with the increasing amount of data we are collecting from our solar system.
假如你想给距地面36000公里的同步卫星发送指令
Say you wanted to send a command to a satellite placed in a geostationary orbit 36,000km above the Earth.
首先，指令会被调制成无线电波，电磁波的一种
Firstly, the command gets converted into a radio wave which is a type of electromagnetic radiation
它的速度是每秒30万公里，和光速一样
that travels at 300,000 kilometers per second, the speed of light.
当指令被调制成电磁波后，地面站的天线会把信号送到卫星
Once the command is converted into a signal, a ground station antenna will then transmit that signal towards the Satellite
卫星会使用其敏锐的天线接收信号
which will use it’s very sensitive antenna to receive the signal.
然后，机载系统会把信号转换成机载计算机能懂的代码
Then, the onboard systems will convert that signal into code which the onboard computers can understand.
多数卫星是有上行和下行功能的，允许把数据传回地球
Most satellites will have an uplink and a downlink to allow the Satellite to send data back to Earth.
在1962年，NASA意识到阿波罗任务需要一种全新的通信系统
In 1962, NASA realized that it would need a brand new communications system for the Apollo missions.
不光是因为阿波罗任务去的地方比之前都要远
Not only would the Apollo missions be going much further than any previous missions,
还因为任务中要同时和三位宇航员、两个不同的航天器通信
they would also be communicating with 3 astronauts working in 2 different spacecraft
并将遥测数据和电视直播画面传回地球
as well as sending telemetry and live television images back to Earth.
为此，他们研发了一种叫“统一S波段”的系统
They developed a system called “Unified S-band”
它可以把原本用不同频率发送的遥测、指令、声音、电视信号
which could send: telemetry, command, voice and television data using different frequencies
统一到只用一个天线发送
but combined into a single antenna.
该系统通过地球各地的地面站与阿波罗飞船通信
This system would communicate with the Apollo spacecraft via fixed ground stations placed around the Earth.
这使得任务控制中心可以在任务中与宇航员保持通信
This would allow mission control to have continuous communication with the astronauts during the mission
除了飞船在月球背面的那段时间
apart from when the spacecraft curved around the far side of the moon,
那段时间信号会消失40分钟，然后他们会在月球另一侧出现
where the signal would be lost until they reappeared on the other side 40 minutes later.
在那段时间里，宇航员必须为一次关键轨道机动点燃发动机
During this time, the astronauts had to fire up the engines in a critical maneuver
保证他们之后能在月球另一侧出现
to make sure they reappeared on the other side of the moon.
如果他们点火成功，他们就会进入预定轨道
If the crew had a successful burn, it would set them on the expected trajectory,
任务控制中心就能准时恢复和阿波罗8号的通信
meaning Mission Control knew exactly when they would regain communication with the Apollo 8 crew.
休斯顿：阿波罗8号，这里是休斯顿，完毕×2
HOUSTON: Apollo 8, Houston over. Apollo 8, Houston over.
阿波罗8号：休斯顿，这里是阿波罗8号
APOLLO 8: Houston, this is Apollo 8.
休斯顿：收到收到，你们已经进入月球轨道了
HOUSTON: We've got it, we've got it. Apollo 8 now in lunar orbit.
休斯顿：我们这屋里一片欢呼，这里是休斯顿阿波罗控制中心……
HOUSTON: There's a cheer in this room. This is Apollo control in Houston…
当然，环绕地球的卫星看不到地面站时也会发生这种信号丢失
Of course, this loss of signal can also happen to satellites orbiting Earth
when the transmitter has no clear path to the satellite.
为避免此事，NASA建立了太空通信网络
To get around this, NASA set up the Space Network,
使用同步卫星作为其它卫星到地面的数据中继
which uses satellites in geostationary orbits to relay data from other satellites to fixed ground stations.
这让近地轨道所有卫星都有了信号覆盖
This provides continuous global coverage for all Earth orbits.
太空通信网络能覆盖近地轨道的卫星，那离地球远得多的卫星怎么办？
The Space Network may cover satellites in Earth’s orbit, but what about satellites that are much further away?
卫星能环绕地球最远的距离
The furthest distance a satellite can orbit the Earth
是地球和太阳引力相等的时候，距离大约是150万公里
before the gravitational force of the Sun equals that of the Earth is around 1.5million kilometres.
可数十亿公里之外的卫星怎么办？
But what about satellites that are BILLIONS of kilometres away?
离地球最远的人造物体是旅行者1号探测器
The furthest man-made object from Earth is the Voyager 1 space probe.
它在1977年发射，用于研究外太阳系
It was launched in 1977 to study the outer solar system.
它目前离地球200亿公里，速度每小时62000公里
It is currently 20 BILLION kilometres away from Earth and travelling at 62,000km/h.
太空通信网络的天线不够与深空探测器之间收发信号
The transmitters used by the Space Network aren’t powerful enough to reach and receive data from deep space satellites.
所以对于这种距离的卫星，我们需要一种叫“深空网络”的东西去通信
For satellites this far away, we need something called the Deep Space Network in order to communicate.
深空网络由位于美国、西班牙、澳大利亚的三组天线阵组成
The Deep Space Network consists of antenna complexes at three locations around the world in: America, Spain and Australia.
它们刚好间隔120度分布在地球上
These facilities are equally spaced 120 degrees apart on Earth.
每组天线有一个70米直径天线和两个小一点的高效天线
Each complex has a 70 meter antenna as well as two smaller high efficiency antennas.
近地卫星常使用低增益全向天线
Satellites close to Earth typically use low gain antennas which spread their signals in every direction
使得很容易能从地球接收它们的信号
making it relatively easy to them pick them up here on Earth.
而深空的卫星则会使用高增益天线
Satellites in deep space use high gain antennas
将电磁波聚焦到一个方向向地球发射
which focus their radiowaves to achieve a much stronger signal strength once it reaches Earth.
深空通信的需求一直在提升
The demands placed on deep space communication systems are continuously increasing.
截至2016年3月，火星勘测轨道飞行器传回了超过300T的数据
As of March 2016, the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter had returned more than 300 terabits of data,
而我们还在不停发射更多的深空卫星
and as we continue to launch more and more satellites into deep space,
NASA估计未来十年我们太空通信的容量会增长十倍
NASA estimates that our space communications capability will need to grow by a factor of 10 in the next decade.
所以，当我们仰望星空的时候，不要忘记我们送去的勇士们
So, as we continue to look further into space, it’s good to know that the brave little spacecrafts
渺小的它们在太阳系边缘仍能不断告诉我们那里是什么样的
that we send out to the edges of our solar system are able to talk back to us and tell us what it’s like out there.
字幕翻译给虫，欢迎点赞投币收藏转发分享评论关注充电~
如果你有什么问题，欢迎在评论区讨论
If you have any questions be sure to leave them in the comments below
记得关注，这样我们能继续学习一个太空姿势
and make sure you’re subscribed so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space.
感谢观看，我们下期见
Thank you very much for watching and I’ll see you in the next video.